This tiny creature
delivers the FASTEST punch
on Earth. Forget
Mike Tyson; the Mantis
Shrimp hits
with the force of a
.22 caliber bullet,
reaching speeds of 50
miles per hour
from a standing start.
Its clubs can shatter
aquarium glass instantly.
But it’s not just
brute force. When
it punches, it creates
superheated cavitation bubbles
that can boil water,
generating a secondary,
even more devastating
shockwave. And its eyes?
They're alien. Unlike
humans with three color
receptors, Mantis Shrimp
have a staggering sixteen!
They can see
polarized light and even
some types of cancer.
Imagine perceiving the
world with such an
immense spectrum of
color and hidden
signals. What other hidden
senses are out
there, waiting to be
discovered?